export const JEWELLERYA2011 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Select an organic material used in making a jewellery item from the options below.",
A: "Brass",
B: "Cane",
C: "Platinum",
D: "Silver",
answer: "B. Cane",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Good and effective packaging increases the demand for jewllery items because they",
A: "become expensive.",
B: "cause inflation.",
C: "glamorise the content.",
D: "make people spend.",
answer: "C. glamorise the content.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Which of the following options can be described as a three-dimensional form?",
A: "Bracelet or a queen",
B: "Flyers for exhibition",
C: "Sketches of earrings",
D: "Slide show of chains",
answer: "A. Bracelet or a queen",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Brass is not pickled immediately after annealing because",
A: "it becomes brittle.",
B: "it changes colour.",
C: "the grains wear off.",
D: "the metal tarnishes.",
answer: "C. the grains wear off.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The most appropriate lubricant applied on a sawblade during piercing is",
A: "beeswax.",
B: "candle.",
C: "kerosene.",
D: "soap.",
answer: "C. kerosene.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Which of the following should be used first in multiple soldering?",
A: "Easy solder",
B: "Hard solder",
C: "Medium solder",
D: "Soft solder",
answer: "D. Soft solder",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Identify the best working surface for soldering.",
A: "Bench top",
B: "Cement floor",
C: "Charcoal block",
D: "Table top",
answer: "C. Charcoal block",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Which of these characteristics differentiates a mineral from an animal source material?",
A: "Beauty",
B: "Durability",
C: "Hardness",
D: "Gravity",
answer: "C. Hardness",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. An understanding of the basic design process leads to a better application of",
A: "elements.",
B: "layout,",
C: "principles.",
D: "prototype.",
answer: "C. principles.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Annealing of a work-hardening copper wire will",
A: "contaminate the metal.",
B: "improve its streak.",
C: "make it malleable.",
D: "reduce its conductivity.",
answer: "C. make it malleable.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Trupmg of the shank of an engagement ring could be done using a",
A: "half-round file.",
B: "metal spatula.",
C: "flat marble.",
D: "scratch brush.",
answer: "A. half-round file.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. When a copper plate coated with black asphaltum is immersed in nitric solution, the",
A: "asphaltum melts.",
B: "asphaltum becomes resistant.",
C: "metal corrodes.",
D: "metal hardens.",
answer: "B. asphaltum becomes resistant.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. In business, the concept of realizing equal amount from sales as the total cost of production is referred to as",
A: "break even analysis.",
B: "going price system.",
C: "market penetration.",
D: "price discrimination.",
answer: "A. break-even analysis.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Beads worn around the calves of babies are to",
A: "check the growth.",
B: "decorate the baby.",
C: "seek fortune.",
D: "strengthen the body.",
answer: "B. decorate the baby.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Finishing of jewellery items by enamelling is successfully executed on",
A: "fabric.",
B: "glass.",
C: "metal.",
D: "plastic.",
answer: "C. metal.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. A brooch designed and produced based on floral pattern components could be joined permanently by",
A: "flapping.",
B: "riveting.",
C: "sewing.",
D: "thonging.",
answer: "B. riveting.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The social contribution a jeweller to a nation is through",
A: "being friendly and appreciative.",
B: "the creative use of ornaments,",
C: "producing ornaments for gifts.",
D: "years of hard work and experience.",
answer: "B. the creative use of ornaments.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. A necklace is functional when it is",
A: "beautiful.",
B: "colourful.",
C: "expensive.",
D: "wearable.",
answer: "D. wearable.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. In soldering, flux",
A: "increases oxidation.",
B: "prevents oxidation,",
C: "quickens reaction.",
D: "slows the reaction.",
answer: "B. prevents oxidation.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The property of metal which enables it to reflect light after polishing is",
A: "conductivity.",
B: "ductility",
C: "hardness.",
D: "lustre.",
answer: "D. lustre.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Which of these materials is used for detecting the annealing point of aluminium?",
A: "Lime juice",
B: "Loam",
C: "Pumice powder",
D: "Soap",
answer: "C. Pumice powder.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The device for creating holes in glass beads during firing is",
A: "bradawl.",
B: "cassava leaf stalk.",
C: "needle.",
D: "plantain leaf stalk.",
answer: "B. cassava leaf stalk.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. A metal, heated to become red hot",
A: "racks.",
B: "expands.",
C: "melts.",
D: "shrinks.",
answer: "B. expands.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which of these techniques will result in raising the surface of a jewellery item?",
A: "Embossing",
B: "Filing",
C: "Piercing",
D: "Texturing",
answer: "A. Embossing",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Select the suitable tool for cutting bamboo into pieces for jewellery work from the following:",
A: "Hacksaw",
B: "Scriber",
C: "Snip",
D: "Shears",
answer: "D. Shears",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The most appropriate tool for boring a hole on a metal sheet is the",
A: "bodkin.",
B: "hand drill.",
C: "jeweller’s saw.",
D: "scriber.",
answer: "B. hand drill.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Oxides formed on the worked-on metals are best removed by",
A: "enamelling.",
B: "etching,",
C: "pickling.",
D: "riveting.",
answer: "C. pickling.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. A metal that can be hammered and pulled is said to be",
A: "brittle,",
B: "fusible.",
C: "malleable",
D: "tough.",
answer: "C. malleable",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Which of these activities can easily cause an accident in a jewellery workshop?",
A: "Hanging tools on racks.",
B: "Keeping all tools in boxes.",
C: "Opening windows for ventilation.",
D: "Oiling tools on the floor.",
answer: "D. Oiling tools on the floor.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. A serious student in jewellery can become a",
A: "blacksmith.",
B: "lapidary.",
C: "metallurgist.",
D: "welder.",
answer: "B. lapidary.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Select from the options below, the tool used to pick a newly fabricated neck chain from a pickling solution.",
A: "Callipers",
B: "Pliers",
C: "Thong",
D: "Tweezers",
answer: "D. Tweezers",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Clay used in fabricating a jewellery item should be",
A: "bone dry.",
B: "hard.",
C: "leather hard",
D: "soft.",
answer: "C. leather hard",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Lacquer is used in jewellery as a",
A: "finish",
B: "fixative",
C: "pickle",
D: "tan.",
answer: "A. finish",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Select the most suitable binder used in jeweller}’ from the following options:",
A: "Acrylic",
B: "Asphaltum",
C: "Glue",
D: "Gum tragacanth",
answer: "D. Gum tragacanth",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. An indirect risk a jeweller might face in establishing a small scale industry is",
A: "fire.",
B: "lack of sales due to site.",
C: "misuse of capital.",
D: "theft.",
answer: "B. lack of sales due to site.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Identify the natural material among the options below.",
A: "Leatherette.",
B: "Pebble.",
C: "Styrofoam.",
D: "Thermoplastic.",
answer: "B. Pebble",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Which of the options below is a linking technique?",
A: "Annealing",
B: "Embossing",
C: "Hinging,",
D: "Repousse",
answer: "C. Hinging.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. For smoothing a sheet of copper, use",
A: "caburundum.",
B: "emery cloth.",
C: "lacquer.",
D: "pickling solution.",
answer: "B. emery cloth.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The cross-section of a wire can be reduced by",
A: "buffing.",
B: "drawing.",
C: "planishing.",
D: "texturing.",
answer: "B. drawing.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. When mounting jewellery items for exhibition, avoid",
A: "clustering items.",
B: "creating colour scheme.",
C: "decorative flowers.",
D: "free movement.",
answer: "A. clustering items.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]